Since 2003, a special type of scam targeting the elderly
Seit 2003 zielt eine Betrugsmasche auf alte Leute
called the money transfer scam has proliferated in Japan.
in Japan ab, der Überweisungsbetrug.
Financial damages increased every year, reaching 56.5 billion yen in 2014.
Der finanzielle Schaden stieg jährlich und belief sich 2014 auf 56,5 Milliarden Yen.
Now, in 2019, scammers have changed their techniques,
2019 haben die Betrüger ihre Masche geändert,
and the damage continues.
und der Betrug geht weiter.
Careful!
Vorsichtig!
Get him in!
Schafft ihn rein!
Shut your mouth!
Klappe!
Let go of me!
Lasst mich los!
I'm the manager!
Ich bin der Manager!
Shit!
Scheiße!
-Get out! -Come on!
-Raus! -Los!
Move!
Bewegung!
Hurry up!
Beeilung!
Stop struggling!
Hör auf zu zappeln!
Sit down!
Setz dich!
Good morning!
Guten Morgen!
EPISODE 5
FOLGE 5
Thanks for making it out here, Mr. Manager.
Danke fürs Kommen, Herr Manager.
What are you trying to achieve by doing this?
Was willst du damit erreichen?
You wanna rat me out to Kanbe?
Willst du mich an Kanbe verpfeifen?
Why don't you at least hear me out?
Warum hörst du mir nicht erst mal zu?
If you do, you might just have a change of heart.
Wenn ja, könntest du deine Meinung ändern.
Hear you out? About what?
Dir zuhören? Weswegen?
I'm going to rob you!
Ich werde dich ausrauben!
Well, to be precise, we're going after Kanbe.
Um genau zu sein, sind wir hinter Kanbe her.
He's opened up nine stores now, right?
Er hat jetzt neun Läden eröffnet, stimmt's?
If we do this right, the payoff will be unbelievable.
Wenn wir es richtig anfangen, wird der Ertrag unglaublich.
I want information!
Ich brauche Informationen!
-Information? -About Kanbe's movements.
-Informationen? -Über Kanbes Vorhaben.
I haven't been able to find any of his weaknesses yet.
Ich konnte noch keine Schwäche entdecken.
Of course, you'd get a cut as well.
Natürlich bekommst du auch einen Anteil.
How about ten percent?
Wie wäre es mit zehn Prozent?
It's a good deal, right?
Ein guter Handel, oder?
Give me a high five!
Schlag ein!
It hurts!
Das tut weh!
Come on now.
Komm jetzt.
You know, this is your little punk friend's fault.
Daran ist dein idiotischer kleiner Freund schuld.
I'm sorry, but...
Tut mir leid, aber...
you've left me without a choice!
...du hast mir keine Wahl gelassen!
-Go ahead and do it. -What?
-Nur zu, mach. -Was?
You're going to fail. Mark my words.
Du wirst versagen. Merk dir das.
-You little... -How dare you!
-Du kleiner... -Was fällt dir ein!
Wait, wait, wait!
Warte!
You've piqued my interest.
Du hast mein Interesse geweckt.
What exactly do you mean by that?
Was genau heißt das?
Isn't it obvious?
Ist das nicht offensichtlich?
You and Kanbe-san aren't even in the same universe.
Du und Kanbe-san lebt nicht mal im selben Universum.
You don't stand a chance.
Du hast keine Chance.
What a disappointment.
Wie enttäuschend.
I thought you'd say something a little more clever.
Ich dachte, du sagst was Schlaueres.
Here.
Hier.
Okay, okay.
Ok.
It hurts!
Das tut weh!
Of course it hurts, you idiot!
Natürlich tut es weh, du Idiot!
If I'm not careful, you could die!
Wenn ich nicht aufpasse, könntest du sterben!
I'm going to barbecue you!
Ich werde dich grillen!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, until you agree to help,
Hey, bis du uns helfen willst,
I'm going to roast every last piece of your body to the bone.
röste ich jede Körperstelle bis auf den Knochen.
So? Will you do it? Will you help me steal from Kanbe?
Also? Machst du es? Hilfst du mir, Kanbe zu bestehlen?
All right then. Well, tell me when you change your mind.
Na gut. Sag mir, wenn du deine Meinung änderst.
Here we go!
Es geht los!
-Stop! -Good evening.
-Halt! -Guten Abend.
Is this the Yamada residence?
Ist hier das Haus der Yamadas?
No! Can't you see that for yourself?
Nein! Siehst du das nicht?
It's not?
Nicht?
I must have gotten it wrong.
Dann habe ich es missverstanden.
Sorry about that.
Tut mir leid.
-Who the hell was that? -He walked off.
-Wer war das? -Er ist weggegangen.
Hey, don't just stand there like an idiot.
Steh nicht blöd rum.
What if he tells someone?
Was, wenn er es jemandem sagt?
-Go follow him! -Yes, sir!
-Folg ihm! -Ja!
Excuse me, is this the Yamada residence?
Verzeihung, ist hier das Haus der Yamadas?
Hey! Hurry up and stop him!
Hey! Halt ihn schnell auf!
-Yamada-san? -He's bothering the neighbors.
-Yamada-san? -Er belästigt die Nachbarn.
Is this the Yamada residence?
Ist hier das Haus der Yamadas?
Who is that? A friend of yours?
Wer ist das? Ein Freund von dir?
-Whatever. Make him sit down on the chair. -Is there a Yamada here?
-Egal. Setz ihn auf den Stuhl. -Gibt es hier einen Yamada?
-What are you doing? -Excuse me?
-Was machst du? -Wie bitte?
Are you high or something?
Bist du high?
Whatever. So? What you gonna do?
Egal. Also? Was wirst du tun?
Stop it!
Hör auf!
Hey! Don't do that!
Hey! Mach das nicht!
I'm sorry! I said I'm sorry!
Tut mir leid! Ich sagte doch, es tut mir leid!
Please! Save me!
Bitte! Rettet mich!
What the hell is going on? Carlos, go check it out.
Was zum Teufel ist da los? Carlos, sieh nach.
What? Me?
Was? Ich?
Yes, you!
Ja, du!
I'm Yamada. That's Makoto.
Ich bin Yamada. Das ist Makoto.
-I'm Carlos. -So, it's you, then!
-Ich bin Carlos. -Also bist du es!
I said go check it out!
Ich sagte, schau nach!
Hey, who did you call here?
Wer hat dich gerufen?
-I don't know him. -Liar!
-Ich kenne ihn nicht. -Lügner!
Help me!
Helft mir!
I'm going to kill you!
Ich bring dich um!
So, you are Yamada-san?
Bist du Yamada-san?
Yes, I'm Yamada!
Ja, ich bin Yamada!
Makoto, help me!
Makoto, hilf mir!
I'll apologize to Kanbe, I swear! Mako--
Ich entschuldige mich bei Kanbe, versprochen! Mako...
-Makoto! -I'll be leaving, then.
-Makoto! -Ich geh dann mal.
Makoto! Makoto! Hey!
Makoto! Hey!
Makoto! Save me!
Makoto! Rette mich!
Hey! Say thank you to Seimiya.
Hey! Bedank dich bei Seimiya.
He saw you getting kidnapped and called me right away.
Er sah, wie du entführt wurdest und rief mich sofort an.
It's a good thing he remembered the license plate number.
Gut, dass er sich das Nummernschild gemerkt hat.
We know the plate numbers and addresses of everyone who works for us.
Wir kennen die Nummernschilder und Adressen aller Mitarbeiter.
That's why I was able to send help so quickly.
Darum konnte ich so schnell Hilfe schicken.
Who is that person?
Wer ist dieser Mensch?
Onuma.
Onuma.
Onuma?
Onuma?
He's a jack-of-all-trades of sorts.
Er ist ein Alleskönner.
You probably won't be seeing him again, so forget about it.
Du wirst ihn wohl nie mehr sehen, also vergiss ihn.
What happened to Yamada-san?
Was ist mit Yamada-san passiert?
Yamada...
Yamada...
I wish I could meet with him and express my gratitude one more time.
Ich wünschte, ich könnte ihm noch einmal danken.
After all, he's the one who introduced you to this job.
Schließlich hat er dir zu diesem Job verholfen.
I'm in his debt.
Ich stehe in seiner Schuld.
-Kusano. -Yes?
-Kusano. -Ja?
You've passed the point of no return.
Du kannst nicht mehr zurück.
You have to put your life on the line for this job.
Du hast dein Leben für diesen Job riskiert.
You can't go back to your normal life, now. So...
Du kannst nicht normal weiterleben. Also...
now you need to do whatever it takes to make money.
...musst du jetzt alles tun, um Geld zu verdienen.
Mom?
Mama?
Hey.
Hey.
You're alive?
Du lebst?
I'm sorry for what I did.
Was ich getan habe, tut mir leid.
I'm apologizing, so can you call Kanbe off?
Ich entschuldige mich, also pfeif Kanbe zurück.
You know I can't do that.
Du weißt, das kann ich nicht.
There's no going back.
Es gibt kein Zurück.
To what?
Zu was?
-There's no going back. -What?
-Es gibt kein Zurück. -Was?
-There's no-- -Please stop!
-Es gibt... -Hör bitte auf!
There's no going back for you now.
Für dich gibt es kein Zurück mehr.
You can't go back! You can't go back!
Du kannst nicht mehr zurück!
-Stop! -You...
-Hör auf! -Du...
can't go back.
...kannst nicht mehr zurück.
Starting today, we're changing things.
Ab heute ändern wir einige Dinge.
We've hit seven targets this week
Wir haben diese Woche sieben Opfer gefunden
and made 36 million yen.
und 36 Millionen Yen verdient.
Our hit rate is through the roof, thanks to the new register,
Unsere Trefferquote ist hoch, dank dem neuen Register,
but at this rate, we'll use it up in no time.
aber in diesem Tempo sind wir im Nu durch.
It'll be difficult to reach our quota of 120 million.
Es wird schwer, die Quote von 120 Millionen zu erreichen.
That's true. We only have 400 targets left.
Stimmt. Es sind nur noch 400 Nummern übrig.
That's why we're changing things. Gouriki.
Darum ändern wir etwas. Gouriki.
Put aside the new contacts and go for the seven targets we've already hit.
Leg die neuen Nummern weg. Hol die sieben aktuellen Opfer raus.
Use the rager act to bleed them dry.
Nimm den Wut-Akt, um sie auszubluten.
Fine, but if I push it too hard, they'll go to the police.
Gut, aber wenn ich zu sehr dränge, geht jemand zur Polizei.
If that happens, tell them that even if you're arrested,
Wenn das passiert, sag, selbst wenn du verhaftet wirst,
your friends will go after them.
sind deine Freunde hinter ihnen her.
Even if it's a bluff, as long as we scare them, we win.
Auch wenn es ein Bluff ist, gewinnen wir, wenn sie erschrecken.
We have to get them to pay as much as they can.
Sie müssen so viel zahlen wie möglich.
-Got it. -Seimiya.
-Verstanden. -Seimiya.
Do you know the dead person scam?
Kennst du den Toten-Betrug?
I've heard of it.
Schon davon gehört.
You tell targets that their deceased relative borrowed money, right?
Man erzählt den Opfern, der tote Verwandte hätte sich Geld geliehen.
Right. This register has the name, death date and professions
Genau. Hier stehen Name, Todestag und Beruf
of the targets' recently deceased husbands and wives.
des verstorbenen Partners der Opfer.
This information will definitely help.
Diese Informationen helfen sicher.
Take Kurusu and Mori and modify the scripts from the illegitimate child
Ändere mit Kurusu und Mori die Skripte des unehelichen Kindes
and embezzlement bluffs to make it work.
und des Unterschlagungsbetrugs, damit es funktioniert.
Got it.
Verstanden.
Hey...
Hey...
This register shows how much money some of the targets are keeping at home.
Auf dem Register steht, wie viel Geld das Opfer zu Hause hat.
Maybe we could lure them out of the house
Locken wir sie doch aus dem Haus
and go in and filch the place as soon as they leave.
und filzen, sobald sie weg sind.
"Filch"?
"Filzen"?
It means rob.
Das heißt ausrauben.
Don't be an idiot.
Sei nicht dumm.
Why? It'll be quick.
Warum? Das geht schnell.
Our job is to scam people.
Wir sollen Leute betrügen.
-If we start robbing people, that's-- -A crime.
-Ausrauben ist... -Ein Verbrechen.
Scamming is also a crime.
Betrug ist auch ein Verbrechen.
-It's a business. -Let's put that aside for now.
-Es ist ein Geschäft. -Sparen wir uns das.
Actually, I know a few people who could help us out.
Ich kenne ein paar Leute, die uns helfen könnten.
If we give them a cut, they'll do it.
Wenn wir ihnen was abgeben, tun sie es.
-Absolutely not. -Why not? It's a good idea.
-Sicher nicht. -Warum nicht? Das ist eine gute Idee.
I don't need ideas like that.
Solche Ideen brauche ich nicht.
We won't be using any means outside of scamming.
Wir machen nichts außer Betrug.
Start with what I just told you.
Fangt mit dem an, was ich gesagt habe.
-Let's do it. -Okay.
-Na los. -Ok.
Fine.
Gut.
Himeka?
Himeka?
-What's wrong? -Misaki...
-Was ist los? -Misaki...
I was told not to say anything, but...
Ich soll nichts sagen, aber...
-Takezo-san... -What?
-Takezo-san... -Was?
How did it get like this in a week?
Wie kam es in einer Woche dazu?
I told you, I've got back pain!
Ich sagte doch, Rückenschmerzen!
What if I hurt my back trying to stand up?
Was, wenn ich mir den Rücken beim Aufstehen verletze?
Would you take responsibility if that happened?
Würdest du die Verantwortung dafür übernehmen?
But...
Aber...
You're just an employee,
Du bist nur eine Angestellte,
so stop telling me what to do! I'm paying for this!
also sag mir nicht, was ich tun soll! Ich bezahle dafür!
Now clean all of this up. Come on!
Jetzt räum das auf. Los!
Not again...
Nicht schon wieder...
I'm sorry. I did it again.
Tut mir leid. Ich habe es wieder getan.
Now that I'm older, I lose my temper so easily.
Im Alter verliere ich schnell meine Beherrschung.
I'm sorry, Kusano-san. I'm sorry!
Tut mir leid, Kusano-san.
Don't worry. It's okay.
Keine Sorge. Schon gut.
You don't have to clean anymore,
Du musst nicht mehr putzen,
so come here and sit with me for a bit.
also setz dich eine Weile zu mir.
I'll just clean this up real quick.
Ich räume das nur schnell auf.
Let's watch some TV! Look, I have some snacks.
Schauen wir fern! Ich habe Snacks.
Really, don't worry about me.
Wirklich, schon gut.
That feels so good.
Das fühlt sich so gut an.
I'm so happy, Daddy. That's so good!
Ich bin so glücklich, Papa. Das ist so gut!
Daddy... that's...
Papa... das ist...
I want to have all of you.
Ich will alles von dir.
Please!
Bitte!
Makoto is involved with the yakuza?
Hat Makoto mit der Yazuka zu tun?
Are you sure?
Sicher?
Himeka is a bit of an airhead, but she wouldn't make this up.
Himeka ist ein Hohlkopf, aber das würde sie nicht erfinden.
What should we do?
Was sollen wir tun?
Watch out!
Passt auf!
Watch where you're going, kid! You should apologize!
Passt auf, wo ihr hinlauft! Ihr solltet euch entschuldigen!
Yes, that's correct.
Ja, das stimmt.
Your deceased husband has another child who will be turning 20 this year.
Ihr verstorbener Mann hatte ein Kind, das dieses Jahr 20 wird.
He's very upset right now.
Er ist gerade sehr aufgebracht.
That's too loud!
Das ist zu laut!
I'm sorry. Like I said, he's very upset, and he says he wants to go confront you.
Tut mir leid. Ich sagte ja, er ist sehr aufgebracht und will Sie konfrontieren.
-He has a lawyer and-- -Stop whining and just pay for it!
-Er hat einen Anwalt und... -Jammer nicht und zahl einfach!
-I'll set your house on fire! -Excuse me...
-Ich zünde dein Haus an! -Entschuldigung...
What? The police?
Was? Die Polizei?
Great! I dare you to call them!
Toll! Ruf sie ruhig an!
-I know people! -He is too loud.
-Ich kenne Leute! -Er ist zu laut.
If something happens to me, they'll kill you!
Wenn mir etwas passiert, bringen sie dich um!
What?
Was?
That's right, yeah!
Genau, ja!
You should've said that from the beginning!
Das hättest du von Anfang an sagen sollen!
Got it!
Geschafft!
What are our profits now?
Wie hoch ist unser Verdienst?
-About 80 million yen. -80 million?
-Etwa 80 Millionen Yen. -Achtzig Millionen?
Quiet down.
Ruhe.
Profits of 80 million in only two weeks...
Ein Gewinn von 80 Millionen in nur zwei Wochen...
You're really something else, Kusano.
Du bist was Besonderes, Kusano.
I knew you were a genius!
Du Genie!
It's 100% thanks to the new register.
Das verdanken wir dem neuen Register.
That's true. But at this rate, we can reach our goal, right?
Stimmt. Aber in diesem Tempo können wir unser Ziel erreichen.
No, not necessarily.
Nein, nicht unbedingt.
There's only 30 names left on the new register.
Es sind nur noch 30 Namen übrig.
We don't have many alternatives left.
Wir haben kaum Alternativen.
If we go to them like, "We ran out of names,"
Wenn wir ihnen sagen: "Wir haben keine Namen mehr",
they'll probably kill us.
bringen sie uns wohl um.
If we don't do something, we're in trouble.
Wenn wir nichts tun, bekommen wir Ärger.
You'll think of something.
Dir fällt schon was ein.
What? How do you figure?
Was? Woher weißt du das?
I feel like we can do anything as long as we have you.
Ich spüre, wir schaffen alles, solange wir dich haben.
I've only done boring work up until now, and nothing ever panned out for me.
Ich hatte nur langweilige Arbeit, nichts hat sich ergeben.
But I feel like anything I do with you will succeed.
Aber alles, was ich mit dir mache, hat Erfolg.
I want to keep working with you even if it kills me.
Ich will weiter mit dir arbeiten, selbst wenn es mich umbringt.
Kanbe-san said it too, right? To do whatever we have to do.
Kanbe-san hat das auch gesagt. Tun, was nötig ist.
That's not what he meant.
Das hat er nicht gemeint.
Hey, Kusano.
Hey, Kusano.
Why exactly are you working so hard at this job?
Warum arbeitest du so hart für diesen Job?
Why?
Warum?
-Well, because... -Your dad's treatment costs?
-Weil... -Die Behandlungskosten deines Vaters?
You told me about that. But you've already paid that off, right?
Du hast mir davon erzählt. Aber die hast du schon bezahlt.
Why are you continuing, then?
Warum machst du weiter?
You don't think about going back to normal?
Denkst du nicht dran, normal weiterzuleben?
-Normal? -Yeah, normal.
-Normal? -Ja, normal.
I can't go back to normal.
Ich kann nicht zurück.
I mean, I won't.
Ich werde es nicht tun.
Some scary stuff happened,
Erschreckende Sachen sind geschehen,
but that woke me up to reality. There's no going back now.
aber das weckte mich. Es gibt jetzt kein Zurück.
I'm high on the adrenaline,
Ich bin high vom Adrenalin,
and like you said, there's no other job like this.
und wie du gesagt hast, es gibt keinen Job wie diesen.
I probably can't quit the money transfer scam anymore.
Ich kann nicht mehr mit dem Überweisungsbetrug aufhören.
That's right. No matter what happens...
Genau. Egal, was passiert...
I can't quit.
...ich kann nicht aufhören.
Mom?
Mama?
Makoto. Explain this.
Makoto. Erklär mir das.
Okay.
Ok.